あぁ 聞いた聞いた｡
大串君？
そう 大串君｡
姉上に つきまとってた
あのｽﾄｰｶｰ➡
えっ？ 誰に聞いたんです？
大串君｡
(新八)銀さん銀さん 大変ですよ！
(銀時)どうした？ ﾒｶﾞﾈ君｡
真選組 局長の
近藤 勲だったんですよ！
Gin, Gin, you won't believe this!
What's up, Four-eyes?
That guy who was stalking my sister!
He's Isao Kondo, the bureau chief of the Shinsengumi!
Oh yeah, I heard.
Huh? Who'd you hear it from?
From Ogushi.
Ogushi?
Yup, Ogushi.
[Gather around, kiddies! It's a big, white doggy!]
[All you nice girls, gather around, too! It's a black-hearted and dishonest guy!]
Granny, give me some pickled seaweed!
(神楽)おばちゃ～ん
酢こんぶ おくれよ｡
(おばちゃん)まいど｡
Thanks for coming!
♪♪(神楽)｢ﾌﾝﾌﾝﾌﾝ 鹿のﾌﾝ｣
Deer poop...
(子供)なんだ これ！
[Odd Jobs Gin]
What the hell is with its size?! No way, absolutely no way!
(子供)このでかさは ない｡
絶対 ないよ｡
(神楽)人んちの前で
何やってるねん ｸｿｶﾞｷども｡
What the hell are you doing hanging around the front of my place, you brats?!
ｴﾛ本でも落ちてたｱﾙか？
Find a dirty magazine or something?
うわっ 酢こんぶ娘だ！
Ah! It's the seaweed girl!
逃げろ！
酸っぱいにおいがうつるぞ！
Run! Or you'll smell sour like her!
(子供たち)わぁ～！
ﾌﾝ ｶﾞｷは 母ちゃんの乳でも
しゃぶってな｡
Humph!  Little brats can go suck their moms' teats.
(犬の鳴き声)
ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ｡
[To Odd Jobs Gin]
わぁ…｡
[Eat Something Sour When You're Tired]
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)え～ それでは 宇宙港
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙから 伝えてもらいましょう｡
All right, let's hear from the Space Port, "Terminal."
Miss Ketsuno!
現場の結野さん｡ 結野ｱﾅ！
Ketsuno! Ana!
(結野ｱﾅ)はい 現場の結野です｡
Ketsuno here!
ここ ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙでは
詰めかけた報道陣が➡
Here at the Terminal, hoards of reporters are waiting for the arrival of Prince Hata.
ﾊﾀ皇子の到着を
今や遅しと待ちかねています｡
(結野)あっ
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙのｹﾞｰﾄが 開きます！
Oh, the gate at the Terminal is opening!
ﾊﾀ皇子の宇宙船が
到着したもようです｡
It seems Prince Hata's spaceship has arrived.
♪♪～
(結野)今回 再び 江戸に
いらっしゃった ﾊﾞｶ皇子…➡
On his return visit to Edo, Prince Baka...uh,
あ いや ﾊﾀ皇子は➡
I mean, Prince Hata will be making visits to the newly constructed Oedo Zoo,
新設された
大江戸動物園をはじめ➡
多くの 動物園や水族館を
回られるそうです｡
along with many other zoos and aquariums.
あっ 現れました！ ﾊﾀ皇子です！
Oh, there he is! It's Prince Hata of the Midland Star Planet!
央国星のﾊﾀ皇子が
そのお姿を お見せになりました！
(ﾊﾀ皇子)久しぶりじゃの 皆の者｡
It's been a long time, everyone! I am overjoyed.
余は 嬉しいぞよ｡
(ﾊﾀ)ﾌﾌ 苦しゅうない｡
苦しゅうないぞよ｡
No need for formalities... No need.
(ﾊﾀ)あっ｡ ぐわっ！
(じい)あぁっ 皇子！
Prince! Who did that?
どいつがやった？
ﾃﾒｴか？ ﾃﾒｴか!?
You?! Or you?!
っていうか お前だろ｡
Was it you?!
以上 現場から…｡
へぇ～｡
Ketsuno reporting from the site.
あの 動物好きの ﾊﾞｶ皇子
また こっちに来てたんすね｡
So that stupid animal-obsessed prince is back. Huh, Gin?
ねぇ 銀さん｡
(いびき)
ちょっと… 聞いてます？
Hey?  Are you listening?
(神楽)ただいまよ～｡
あっ おかえり｡
I'm back.
Welcome back.
ﾄｲﾚｯﾄﾍﾟｰﾊﾟｰ 買ってきてくれた？
はいよ｡
Didja get toilet paper?
Here you go.
神楽ちゃん あのさ…➡
Kagura, listen...
普通 何ﾛｰﾙか入ったﾔﾂ
買ってくるんじゃないの？
don't people usually buy them in packs of several rolls?
これじゃ 誰か お腹こわしたら
対応しきれないよ｡
What if someone gets the big "D"? No way will this be enough.
便所紙くらいで ｶﾞﾀｶﾞﾀうるさいｱﾙ｡
姑か？ お前｡
Quit nagging about the toilet paper!
What are you, my mother-in-law?
(神楽)世の中には 新聞紙を
ﾄｲﾚｯﾄﾍﾟｰﾊﾟｰと呼んで暮らす➡
There are poor samurai in this world who use newspaper for toilet paper!
貧しい侍だっているｱﾙ｡
There aren't any extremists like that! Who told you that anyway?
そんな過激派 いないよ！
誰に聞いたの？
銀ちゃんが言ってたよ｡
Gin said so!
You can't trust anything he says.
ﾀﾞﾒだよ
あの人の言うこと 信じちゃ｡
うるせえなぁ… はっ｡
Shut up.
Don't act like you know it all when your butt is still green, you idol otaku!
ｹﾂの青いｶﾞｷが 偉そうなこと
言ってんじゃねえぞ ｱｲﾄﾞﾙｵﾀｸが！
なんだと!? っていうか
そっちのほうが年下だろうが！
What?! You're younger than me!
Shinpachi, what's that white thing?
新八… その白いの 何だ？
何って… ﾄｲﾚｯﾄﾍﾟｰﾊﾟｰですよ｡
What else? Toilet paper.
そうじゃなくて でかいほう｡
Not that! The big white one!
でかいほうとか 小さいほうとか
下ﾈﾀは やめてくださいよ｡
Can you quit talking about dirty stuff like "big thing" or "little thing"?
大体 いつも 銀さんが
そういうこと言うから➡
It's because of the way you talk that Kagura is...
神楽ちゃんも… いっ？
Gyaaa! What is this?!
わぁ～っ！ 何これ～っ!?
表に落ちてたｱﾙ｡
かわいいでしょ？
I found it outside. Isn't it cute?
落ちてたじゃねえよ！
お前 拾ってくんなら せめて➡
Forget where it was!
If you're gonna pick something up, at least know what it is!
名称のわかるもん拾ってこいや！
定春｡
Sadaharu.
You just named it! You totally made that name up just now!
今 つけたろ!?
明らかに 今 つけたろ!?
(神楽)これ 首輪に挟まってたよ｡
[To Odd Jobs Gin]
This was stuck in his collar.
えっと…？
Let's see... To Odd Jobs Gin.
｢万事屋さんへ｡
申し訳ありませんが
ｳﾁのﾍﾟｯﾄ もらってください｣
I'm very sorry, but please take my pet in.
それだけか？
Is that all?
｢(笑)｣と書いてあります｡
"LOL" in parenthesis.
笑えるかぁ～っ！
(怒)とじ～!!
How can I be laughing! I'm "Mad" in parenthesis!
要するに
捨ててっただけじゃねえか！
In other words, it was abandoned!
万事屋っつったってなぁ
ﾎﾞﾗﾝﾃｨｱじゃねえんだよ！
We're not a charity!
捨ててこい！ ﾍﾟﾍﾟﾍﾟﾍﾟｲ！
嫌ｱﾙ！
Get rid of it! Now! Shoo! Shoo!
Nuh-uh! We abandon it in this heartless town, it'll die!
こんな
優しさのかけらもない町に➡
ほっぽっといたら
死んでしまうよ！
大丈夫だよ ｵﾒｴ｡ 定春なら
ひとりでも やっていけるさ｡
Don't worry. Sadaharu can manage alone.
ｱﾝﾀ 定春の何を知ってんの!?
What do you know about Sadaharu anyway?!
わかってくれるよなぁ 定春…｡
You understand, don't you, Sadaha-
(吠え声)
(ﾊﾀ)あぁ…
やはり 地球は おもしろいのぅ｡
Earth is so much fun!
環境が よいせいか
多種多様な生き物が生息しておる｡
Perhaps it's because the environment is so nice, but there are so many different living things!
何度来ても 飽きぬわ｡
のぅ じい？
I never tire of coming here.
Don't you agree, Jii?
さようでございますなぁ｡
Yes, my prince.
(ﾊﾀ)前回 江戸に来たときは
さんざんな目に遭ったからなぁ｡
The last time I came to Edo, I had a terrible time.
(ﾊﾀ)今回は
江戸中の動物園を調べてでも➡
So now, I wanna check all the zoos in Edo and take back any unusual creatures.
珍しい生物を
手に入れて帰りたいものじゃ｡
のぅ じい？
めんどくせえなぁ｡
Don't you agree, Jii?
What a bother.
何か言ったか？
Did you say something?
いえ 何でもございません ﾊﾞｶ皇子｡
No, nothing, Prince Baka.
You just called me baka.
ﾊﾞｶって言ってんじゃん｡
ﾊﾞｶって言ったの誰だ ｺﾗ！
ﾃﾒｴか!? ﾃﾒｴだろ!?
Who said baka?! You? Or you? It was you, huh?!
(ﾊﾀ)っていうか お前だろ｡
Wasn't it you?
(じい)Ｍ78星雲で発見された
ｳﾙﾄﾗｷﾘﾝです｡
This is the Ultra Giraffe, which was found on Nebula M78.
ﾎﾎﾎ… 愛いﾔﾂじゃのぅ｡
So cute!
ちなみに 人を食べます｡
By the way, it eats people.
(じい)大ﾏｾﾞﾗﾝ雲から来た
ｲｽｶﾝﾀﾞﾙ象です｡
This is the Iscandar Elephant from the Great Mazeran Cloud.
ｺｲﾂも かわいいぞよ｡
This one's cute, too!
ちなみに 鼻が伸びると…➡
By the way, when it stretches its trunk...it eats people.
人を食べます｡
(じい)ﾘﾘﾊﾟｯﾄ星に生息する
ﾌﾟﾁﾍﾟﾝｷﾞﾝです｡
This is the Petit Penguin, which inhabits Lilliput Planet.
これは 安全じゃろうな？
This one better be safe.
そのﾍﾟﾝｷﾞﾝは
人を食べたりしません｡
The penguin doesn't eat people.
が 下にいる白ｸﾏは 人を食べます｡
However, the white polar bear below it does.
余を殺そうとしてるだろ!!
Are you trying to kill me?!
(沖田)しかし 土方さん…➡
Man, Hijikata,
なんで ｵﾚらが 動物探しなんざ
せなならんのですかい？
what are we doing out here looking for an animal?
(土方)ｵﾚにも よくわからん｡
I'm not sure, either.
ただ 今度 来日した
どこぞのお偉いの➡
But I did hear that it's to be presented during an audience with some VIP who's making a visit here.
顔色うかがいだとは 聞いたがな｡
(沖田)そんな 顔も知らねえお方の
顔色うかがうためなら➡
Well, if we don't even know who this VIP is, any animal we catch should suffice.
適当なものを見繕ってけば
かっこはつきますわ｡
(土方)だからよ
その適当なものってのが…｡
Well, by any animal...
ﾃﾒｴ 何やってんだ 総悟！
What the hell are you doing?!
どこぞのお偉いへの
献上品ですわ｡
Something to present to some VIP.
ふざけんな！
いっぺん死ぬか？ ｺﾗｧ!!
Cut it out, or do you wanna die?!
語尾は ｢ﾜﾝ｣にしてくだせえ｡
Can you end your sentences with a bow-wow?
するか!!
Not likely!
…ん？
[Looking for someone to adopt!
Cute, white puppy!
Inquire at Odd Jobs Gin.]
(土方)これは…｡
What's this?
とにかくだ
新しい飼い主が見つかるまで➡
Anyway, until we find someone to adopt him, I'll allow Shigeo to stay here.
茂男を ここで預かるのは
許してやる｡
茂男じゃないでしょ｡
定春っすよ｡
It's not Shigeo! It's Sadaharu.
そのかわり
飼い主が見つかりしだい➡
But once we find another owner, Tatsunori is out of here!
辰則には 出ていってもらうぞ｡
だから 定春だって！
I said it's Sadaharu!
こんなに 定春 かわいいのに
銀ちゃんは なんで 嫌ｱﾙか？
Sadaharu is so cute! Why don't you like him?
女が言う かわいいってのは
男は 信用できねえんだよ｡
Men can't believe what women call "cute."
(神楽)新八も そうｱﾙか？
Shinpachi, are you like that, too?
いかにも かわいい系好きの
ｵﾀｸっぽいﾒｶﾞﾈして➡
Wearing the kind of glasses an otaku who's into cutesy girls would wear.
結局 ﾌｪﾛﾓﾝ系が好きな男ｱﾙか!?
And yet you're into sexy women, too?
ｵﾀｸっぽいってなんだよ!?
Who are you calling otaku?!
(神楽)いいから なでてみるｱﾙ｡
ちょっとかわいく思えるｱﾙ！
Just try petting him! I'm sure you'll think he's cute!
(２人)わぁ～っ！
どう？
ど… どけてよ 神楽ちゃん｡
重いっつうの…｡
G-Get him off me, Kagura.
It's heavy.
(神楽)私の思いが わかったｱﾙね？
So you understand how heavy my heart feels now?
いや その｢思い｣じゃないから…｡
Th-That's not what he meant.
愛されるのは
確かに 重いかもしれない｡
Being loved is a heavy burden.
でも 私と定春は 大丈夫ね！
(定春)ﾜﾝ！
But Sadaharu and I will be okay!
く 苦しい～…｡
さっき食べた ﾁｮｺｺﾛﾈが➡
I-I can't breathe...
It feels like the chocolate coronet I just ate is gonna come out of both ends.
上か下の どっちかからか
ﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰしそうだ…｡
(銀時たちの騒ぎ声)
(お登勢)っていうか
昼間っから うるせえ…｡
They've been making a racket all day!
(騒ぎ声)
おい ﾃﾒｴら！
狭いところで暴れるな！
Hey, quit running around in here!
神楽ちゃん
ちゃんと しつけなきゃ ﾀﾞﾒだよ！
Kagura! You have to train him!
ﾜﾝﾊﾟｸでもいい｡ たくましく育つｱﾙ｡
Even if he's mischievous, I'm gonna raise him strong and healthy!
ｷﾐたちの ﾜﾝﾊﾟｸは
人が死にかねないでしょ！
Your mischievous behavior could kill people!
わぁ～っ!!
どうしました 銀さん！
What's wrong, Gin?
定春のﾔﾂが ｵﾚの ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣の上で
小さいほうのﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰしやがった～！
Sadaharu just made a little debut on my JUMP!
(神楽)小さくﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰって
謙虚な子ｱﾙね～｡
A little debut? You're so modest!
だぁ～っ！
お通ちゃんのﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰｼﾝｸﾞﾙに
ﾃﾞｶﾃﾞｶと ﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰさせちゃってるよ!!
He went on to make a major debut on Otsu's debut single!
お通 ﾌｭｰﾁｬﾘﾝｸﾞ 定春ｱﾙ！
ﾜﾝﾜﾝ！
Otsu featuring Sadaharu!
Sadaharu, why I oughta!
(銀時/新八)定春～…
ﾃﾒｴ いいかげんに…！
S-Sorry...
(銀時/新八)すみません…｡
う～っす｡
What's up?
What's the deal, you coming in here?
なんだよ そっちから来るなんて｡
貸す金なら ねえぞ｡
違うよ｡
I don't have any money to lend you.
That's not it.
家賃を払いにきたんだよ｡
I came to pay the rent.
なんのﾄﾞｯｷﾘだい？
What kind of prank is this?
どっかに ｶﾒﾗが
仕掛けてあるんだろ～？
There must be a hidden camera somewhere.
そうじゃねえよ｡
It's not like that! I just thought I'd at least pay this month's rent.
とりあえず 今月の家賃だけでも
払おうと思ってな｡
ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ…｡
あぁ 確かに 今日は暑いねぇ｡
Yes, it's a hot day today.
ちょ 待てよ｡ ほら これ
名犬ﾗｯｼｰの はとこだから｡
Hey, hold it!
Come on! This is Lassie's second cousin!
家賃１か月分くらいの
価値あるって～｡
He should be worth a month's rent!
ﾌﾗﾝﾀﾞｰｽの犬の いとこでも
いらねえ!!
I don't want it even if it's the cousin of the Dog of Flanders!
えい！
ﾊﾟﾄﾗ～ｯｼｭ!!
…ぐわっ!!
いやぁ あれだ
神楽が 昼寝してる間に➡
OK, here's the plan.
While Kagura is taking a nap, we'll go look for another owner.
こっちから 飼い主を探そうという
魂胆なんだが…｡
魂胆だ って… いいんすか？
Plan? Are you sure? Kagura will be very upset.
神楽ちゃん 怒りますよ？
いいんだよ｡
It's all right.
つらい現実を知って
少女は 大人の階段を上り➡
By experiencing harsh reality, a young girl climbs the stairway to maturity.
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙｵﾀｸは ﾌｧﾝを卒業してゆく｡
And an idol otaku graduates from fandom.
それ ｵﾚか!? ｵﾚのことか!?
ぜってぇ卒業しねえぞ!!
Do you mean me?! Are you talking about me?!
No way! I'll never graduate!
ほ～ら 行くぞ｡ …あっ！
Let's go!
ｺﾗ 動け！ この ﾃﾞｶうんも製造機!!
Hey, move it! You giant poop vendor!
(うなり声)
(２人)あ… あ…｡
(土方)たぶん
この辺りのはずだがな…｡
It should be around here.
(沖田)土方さん｡
ん？
Hijikata...
何やってんだ？ お前｡
What're you doing?
危ないですぜ｡
はぁ？
Watch out.
うわぁ～～っ!!
わあぁ～～っ!!
(定春)ﾜﾝﾜﾝ…！
(土方の悲鳴)
Wh-What?! It's him!
なんだ…？ ｱｲﾂじゃねえか…｡
Mmm... Huh? Sadaharu?
定春…？ 定春～？
Sadaharu?
ようやく 落ち着いたな…｡
He's finally settled down.
いったい どうするんすか？
What're we gonna do?
定春 飼ってくれそうな人なんて
そうそう いないっすよ？
I doubt there's anyone who wants to adopt Sadaharu.
まぁ 心配するな｡
Don't worry. I have an idea.
あてはある｡
うっ…！
Wahh! Another debut!
うあ～っ！ また ﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰした～!!
My house is your idea?!
あてがあるって ｳﾁじゃん！
ｱﾝﾀ ｳﾁに 定春 押しつける気!?
You plan to dump off Sadaharu at my place?!
いや～ だって あれでしょう？
Well, your sister's having trouble with a stalker, right?
ｷﾐのお姉さん ｽﾄｰｶｰに
困ってるんでしょう？
それは この間 銀さんが
解決したじゃないですか～!!
You took care of that the other day!
困ってるときは お互いさまだ｡
ちょうどいいぞ 番犬に｡
We help each other out when we can.
He'll be the perfect guard dog.
だから 人の話 聞こうよ!!
Listen to me, damn it!
噛むなって！
(お妙)あら｡
Don't bite!
Oh?
あなたたち 何をしてるの？
What are you two doing?
もう 定春も 銀ちゃんも
どこに行ったｱﾙか？
Sheesh! Where'd Sadaharu and Gin go?
つうわけで ｺｲﾂを ここで
飼ってくんねえか？
So, you think you could take this dog in?
ｳﾁには ただでさえ
使えない 思春期の男がいるのに➡
We already have a useless adolescent boy.
To take in one more...
もう１人 増えるのはね～｡
使えないは よけいでしょ！
Isn't "useless" a bit harsh?
っていうか 姉上！
これ 犬だから!!
Besides, Sis, this is a dog!
(新八の悲鳴)
Seriously, please! Sadaharu says he prefers it here.
ﾏｼﾞで頼むよ｡ 定春も
ここがいい って言ってんだよ～｡
What do you mean by that?!
(神楽)それ どういうことよ!?
ｹﾞｯ!?
ｱﾀｼの知らないうちに…！
While my back was turned!
いや～ 違う！
これはな 定春のためを思って…｡
No, you've got it all wrong.
This is for Sadaharu's sake.
ひどいよ 銀ちゃん!!
うわぁ～～っ!!
You're terrible, Gin!
なんだ…
結構 好かれてるじゃない｡
Hey, he seems to like you quite a lot.
(神楽の笑い声)
定春～！
Sadaharu!
Come here!
こっち 来るｱﾙよ～！
いや～ すっかり なついちゃって
ほほえましいかぎりだね 新八君｡
Boy, they get on like a house on fire. Makes you wanna smile, huh, Shinpachi?
そうっすね｡ 女の子には やっぱり
大きな犬が似合いますよ 銀さん｡
Yes. I guess girls and big goofy dogs go together, Gin.
(せき込む声)
ﾎﾞｸらには なんで
なつかないんだろうか？
I wonder why it just won't take to us?
なんとか 捨てようとしてるのが➡
It knows that we're trying to get rid of him.
野性の勘で わかるんですよ
銀さん｡
It's the instinct of the wild.
なんで ｱｲﾂには なつくんだろう？
新八君｡
Why is it so attached to her, Shinpachi?
なついてませんよ 銀さん｡
It isn't, Gin.
♪♪～
襲われてるけど 神楽ちゃんが➡
It's attacking her, but Kagura doesn't think anything of it, Gin.
ものともしてないんですよ
銀さん｡
Quit playing around!
なるほど…｡ そうなのか 新八君｡
I see, so that's how it is, huh, Shinpachi.
はい…｡
Yep.
♪♪～
There!
(神楽)よいしょっと…｡ ﾌｩ｡
楽しそうだな おい｡
うん！
You seem to be having fun.
Yup!
私 動物 好きね｡
I love animals.
女の子は みんな
かわいいもの好きよ｡
All girls love cute things. Don't need a reason for that.
そこに 理由いらないよ｡
あれ… かわいいか？
That's cute?
(激突音)
Of course, it's cute!
(神楽)かわいいよ！ こんなに
動物になつかれたの初めて！
This is the first time an animal has gotten so attached to me!
神楽ちゃん
いいかげん 気づいたら…？
Kagura, you should realize it already.
私 昔 ﾍﾟｯﾄ飼ってたことあるｱﾙ｡
I...
...used to have pet long ago.
定春１号！
Sadaharu No.1!
(神楽)ごっさ かわいかった
定春１号｡
Sadaharu No.1 was super cute and I loved him so much.
(神楽)私も ごっさ
かわいがったね！
(神楽)定春１号
外で飼ってたんだけど➡
I kept Sadaharu No.1 outside, but one night, I really, really wanted to sleep with him,
ある日 私 どうしても
一緒に寝たくて➡
親に内緒で 抱いて眠ったね｡
so I snuggled with him under the covers without telling my parents.
そしたら 思いのほか寝苦しくて
悪夢 見たよ｡
I had a nightmare and thrashed around all night.
(悲鳴)
It was a terrible nightmare and when I woke up...
(神楽)
さんざん うなされて起きたら➡
定春 ｶｯﾁｺｯﾁになってたｱﾙ…｡
Sadaharu was lying there stiff.
《泣けばいいのか 笑えばいいのか
わかんないんだけど…》
Should I be laughing or crying?
(神楽)あれから私 動物に触れるの
自ら禁じたね｡
After that, I swore I'd never get close to animals.
力のｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾙ 下手な私じゃ
みんな 不幸にしてしまう…｡
I'm not good at controlling my strength, and I only end up hurting them.
でも この定春なら 私とでも
つりあいがとれるかもしれない｡
But maybe this Sadaharu and I will make a good pair.
He's a gift from the heavens. I'm sure of it, uh-huh.
これ 神様のﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄｱﾙ きっと…｡
あっ！ 酢こんぶ きれてるの
忘れてたね！
I forgot I'm out of pickled seaweed. I'm gonna go and buy some.
ちょっと 買ってくるよ｡
(銀時/新八)えっ!?
Take care of Sadaharu for me!
定春のこと よろしくｱﾙ！
おい ちょっ… 待て…！
(定春)ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ…｡
Hey, wait!
あっ…｡
ううっ…｡
いい～っ…！
(銀時と新八の悲鳴)
おい 定春君…！
Hey, Sadaharu!
銀さ～ん!!
G-G-Gin!
おおっ…！ 銀さ～ん!!
Gin!
助けて～!!
助かった…｡
H-Help!
I'm saved!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
寝顔は かわいいんすけどね…｡
ｺｲﾂは 犬の姿をした凶器だ…｡
He looks cute sleeping like that.
He's a demon in a dog's clothing.
凶暴な犬と ﾏﾆｱの世界には
心 奪われちゃﾀﾞﾒだ！
In a manic world with ferocious dogs, we must watch our hearts!
But after watching Kagura love it so much, it's sorta...
でも 神楽ちゃんが あんなに
かわいがってるのを見ると➡
なんだか…｡
Oh, there you are.
おう ここにいたか…｡
ん…？ あぁ ｵﾒｴらか｡
Huh? You guys?
なんだ？
仕事もせずに 真っ昼間から｡
What's up with you? Don't you even work during the day?
遊び仲間でも お探しですか？
Looking for a companion to have fun with?
ﾃﾒｴなんか 遊びに誘うか｡
ｹﾝｶなら まだしもな！
Like I'd invite you to join our fun! A fight's different, though!
この間 売られたｹﾝｶは➡
That fight you picked last time? I gave it right back to you.
菓子折りつけて
返してやったはずだぜ？
上等だ！ それじゃ 今度は➡
Fine!
Then this time, I'll give it right back to you with a fruit basket as a bonus!
お見舞い用ﾌﾙｰﾂｾｯﾄをつけて
返してやるよ!!
ひぃ～～っ…!!
時に 旦那｡
ｿｲﾂは 旦那の犬ですかい？
By the way... Is that your dog?
別に ｵﾚの犬ってわけじゃねえよ｡
なんだ？ 突然…｡
It's not really my dog. Why you asking?
…って 話 進めてんじゃねえよ!!
Don't go off talking without me!
幕府の上のつながりで➡
There's a certain someone connected to the upper ranks of the government
who's interested in animals like that.
その手の動物を欲しがってる
お方が いやしてね…➡
その犬 真選組で
引き取らせてくだせぇ｡
We'd like you to hand that dog over to the Shinsengumi.
やだね｡
ｵﾒｴらなんかに やらねえよ｡
Forget it. I wouldn't give it to guys like you.
ｵﾚが 真選組の言いなりには
ならねえってこと 忘れんな｡
Don't ever forget that I don't bow down to the Shinsengumi.
(土方)つうか ｵﾚの存在
忘れてんだろ～!!
You're forgetting that I'm standing right here!
まいったな…｡ どうする？ 総悟｡
Damn! What'll we do, Sogo?
やっぱりここは 土方さんが➡
I think you'll just have to end your sentences with bow-wow.
語尾を ﾜﾝにして…｡
するか!!
As if!
銀さん ひょっとして
神楽ちゃんのために…｡
Gin, did you refuse for Kagura's sake?
違えよ！
Naw...
ﾔﾂらに言われたように
したくなかっただけさ｡
I just don't like doing what I'm told.
んっ…？
(うなり声)
(ﾊﾀ)あ～ 世の眼鏡にかなう動物は
なかなか おらんの～｡
Oh...There's no animal that catches my eye.
みんな 帯に短し
たすきに長しじゃ…｡
Every one of them seems to be lacking in something.
(じい)さようでございますな｡
You are right.
(ﾊﾀ)何か よい手は
ないもんかのう？
Isn't there anything we can do?
(銀時と新八の悲鳴)
危なっ!!
(急ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ音)
Look out!
(衝突音)
Jii!
じい～!! なんということを…!!
What have you done?!
Calm down, my prince!
落ち着きなされ 皇子！
I will go and find a time machine.
とりあえず 私めが
ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝを探してくるので…｡
じい ｵﾒｴが落ち着けよ！
(定春の鳴き声)
You calm down, Jii.
(ﾊﾀ)これは…!?
なんということじゃ～！
Wh-What is this?!
(じい)どうなされた？ 皇子｡
(ﾊﾀ)じい これを見よ｡
What's wrong, my prince?
Jii! Look at this!
ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝ 見つかりましたか!?
違えよ ｸｿｼﾞｼﾞｲ!!
Did you find a time machine?!
No! You old geezer!
(じい)これは 犬神…!?
なぜ このような珍種が…｡
This is...a Dog God! What a rare species.
Do you have a rope?
(ﾊﾀ)じい 縄はあるか？
こんなことしていいんですか？
皇子｡
Should we be doing this, my prince?
私ら ただのﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗですな…｡
We're behaving like common criminals.
これは 保護だ｡ こんな貴重な生物
野放しにはできん｡
This is conservation! I can't allow such a precious specimen to stay in the wild!
All right, let's go!
(ﾊﾀ)よ～し いくぞ～｡
(じい)はっ！
Yes, sire.
(ﾊﾀ)ｱﾊ～！
また ｺﾚｸｼｮﾝが増えちゃったぞよ｡
I've added to my collection again!
♪♪(神楽)｢ﾌﾝ ﾌﾝ ﾌﾝ｣
♪♪｢鹿のﾌﾝ｣
Deer poop...
Sadaharu!
(神楽)定春…!?
(ﾊﾀ)前回のときは 銀髪の男や➡
The last time I was here, I had a horrible time
変な娘に
ひどい目に遭わされたが➡
with that silver-haired man and that weird girl.
これで ﾍﾟｽを失った傷も
癒えるというもの…｡
But this'll finally ease the pain of losing Pesu.
(ﾊﾀ)なぁ？ じい｡
さようで…｡
Right, Jii?
Absolutely.
ｷﾞｬ～～ｯ!! ｿﾞ… ｿﾞﾝﾋﾞだ～!!
A-A zombie!
Hey, stop the car, you jerk.
お～い！ 車 止めろ ﾎﾞｹ～！
き… 貴様は あのときの…!?
Y-You again!
いろいろ考えたけどよ➡
I gave it a lot of thought,
やっぱり ｺｲﾂは
勘弁したってくれや｡
but cut me some slack on this one here.
ｱｲﾂ…
相当 気に入ってるみてえなんだ｡
Seems she's really taken a liking to that thing.
何を ﾜｹのわからんことを…！
What are you blabbering about?! Move!
どけ～！
前 見えねえんだよ ﾁｸｼｮｳ!!
I can't see in front of me, dammit!
♪♪～
Wha--?!
どうしたんじゃ？
What's the matter?
(じい)変な娘が
ものすごいｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞで…！
A weird kid is approaching at tremendous speed!
定春 返せ～!!
Give back Sadaharu!
誰じゃ？ 定春って…｡
Who is Sadaharu?!
St-Stay back!
(じい)く… 来るな～!!
ぬお～～っ!!
(じいたちの悲鳴)
《定春 乗ってたの 忘れてた…》
I forgot Sadaharu was on the car.
(神楽)定春～!!
Sadaharu!
ｱﾀｼ… また 同じことを
繰り返してしまったよ…｡
I've gone and...done it...all over again.
'Scuse me, miss.
お嬢さん｡
何が そんなに悲しいんだい？
What are you so sad about?
銀ちゃん！ 定春!!
Gin! Sadaharu!
♪♪～
Sadaharu!
定春!!
Sadaharu! I'm so glad! I'm so, so glad!
定春～！ よかった～！
ﾎﾝﾄ よかったよ～!!
♪♪～
銀ちゃん
飼うの 反対してたのに…｡
Gin, you were so against keeping him.
Hell if I know.
ｵﾚは 知らねえよ｡
面倒みんなら ﾃﾒｴでみな｡
If you're gonna keep it, you take care of it.
ｵﾒｴの給料から ｿｲﾂのｴｻ代
きっちり引いとくからな｡
And I'll be deducting the cost of his food from your salary!
ありがとう 銀ちゃん…｡
Thank you, Gin.
給料なんて
もらったことないけど…｡
Though I've never actually gotten paid.
♪♪～
Let's not come to Earth anymore.
(ﾊﾀ)もう 地球に来んの やめよう｡
(じい)さようでございますな…｡
I agree.
(ｶﾗｽ)ｱﾎ～｡ ｱﾎ～｡ ｱﾎ～｡
Remember to say bow-wow at the end of your sentences, Kondo.
(沖田)語尾は ﾜﾝですぜ｡
近藤さん｡
[Preview]
Find a poster girl from a dango shop?
And you're telling me it's from fifty years ago?!
Listen, pops.
Even if we do find her, she'll be someone who used to be a poster girl.
The next episode: "Look, Overly Sticky Sweet Dumplings Are Not Real Dumplings, You Idiot!"
[Once you grow out of JUMP, go for Weekly Playboy. It has everything from large, medium, to small.]
[Next week's Gintama is a senior fest. Loads of gramps and grannies.]
Ah... Don't go thinkin' there's always some bonus feature for you at the end!
いつも おまけみたいのがあると
思わないように！
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～